Welcome to our training on the customer reviews tool.
Product reviews are an important part of buying and selling in the Amazon store.
They help customers understand the experiences of those who've already purchased products.
And they help sellers identify and correct product and listing issues.
If you're a professional seller internal to a brand enrolled in Amazon Brand Registry, you can use
the customer reviews tool to track product reviews.
You can also use it to respond to customers who've left reviews,
between one and three stars.
Let's find out how to use the customer reviews tool
and go over some basic guidelines for customer communication.
If you meet the
requirements, you can access the customer reviews tool anytime in Seller Central
by hovering over brands in the main menu, then clicking customer reviews.
The
customer reviews tool displays product reviews in chronological order, starting
with the most recent at the top.
It includes reviews for products within a
brand when they're sold by you, as well as other sellers.
Reviews first appear in
the tool within 48 hours of their publication on a product detail page,
and they're retained for 90 days to help you spot trends and coordinate
responses.
You can use the series of filters at the top of the tool to find
specific types of reviews.
Narrow the list to reviews associated with orders
you fulfilled or to orders fulfilled by other sellers.
You can also filter
reviews according to whether a customer has already received a response through
the customer reviews tool.
You can select reviews with one or more star ratings
too, or you can select reviews according to their age.
You can click the include
marked as done filter if you want to see reviews that you previously removed from
the list by checking the mark as done box.
This will resurface reviews that you
marked done in the last 90 days.
The star rating filter can help you find
customer reviews you might want to respond to.
Select the 1 2 and 3 stars
filters then look for contact customer and offer courtesy refund links on the
right-hand side.
If you click contact customer you can select courtesy refund
or customer support as your response type.
If you click offer courtesy refund that
response type will be pre-selected.
You won't be able to select customer
support because the customer previously opted out of communication with Amazon
sellers and only courtesy refunds are now permitted.
Both the courtesy refund and
customer support responses that appear below are automated and uneditable.
The
courtesy refund message offers the customer a full refund and the customer
support message asks the customer for an opportunity to address any issues or
concerns.
After reviewing either type of message you can click the send button to
email it to the customer.
If they reply you'll receive their response via the
buyer seller messaging tool in seller central which you can access by clicking
the envelope icon in the top right corner.
While reviewing one to three star
reviews you may also see a status next to a review instead of a link.
That means
you aren't able to respond.
This could be because you aren't the seller who
fulfilled the order or because the order was placed more than 12 months ago.
Purchases also have to be verified in order for a seller to contact a
customer and they can't be for a digital subscription.
If you receive a reply from
a customer in response to a message sent through the customer reviews tool it's
important to keep in mind that any additional messages you send using buyer
seller messaging must comply with Amazon's customer product reviews policies and
community guidelines.
Please review both in full before communicating with a
customer.
You can search for them in seller central and the Amazon store
respectively.
Note too that customer product reviews policies specifically
prohibit sellers from asking customers to change or remove reviews.
More broadly
they prohibit sellers from attempting to influence customer reviews ratings or
feedback.
While scrolling through reviews in the Amazon store you may discover one
that you suspect violates the community guidelines or customer reviews policies.
In that case click show review details below the review.
On the public customer
review page click report abuse then the report button in the pop-up.
We'll remove
the review from the Amazon store if it violates our policies which means it
will also be removed from the customer reviews tool.
This concludes our training
on the customer reviews tool.
We encourage you to watch additional seller
university videos about other tools and benefits available to brands enrolled in
brand registry.
You can also get more information about the eligibility to
access brand selling benefits by watching videos in our course launch your brand
in the Amazon store.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.